# KATELINN JONES

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



(831) 247-7102



KATIEJONESYO@GMAIL.COM



/KATIEJONESYO



WWW.KATIEJONES.DEV

## TECH STACK

### LANGUAGES

**JavaScript** 

HTML

CSS

Ruby

## TESTING

Jest **OUnit** 

**Supertest** Github Cl

## FRAMEWORKS/ LIBRARIES

React Redux **Express** jQuery **Nodejs** 

## DATABASES

**PostgresSQL** 

## TOOLS

**VSCode Netlify** Heroku Postman **PgAdmin** 

Slack

GitHub

Miro **Photoshop** 

**PyCharm** Figma

Sketch

# **EDUCATION**

#### ALCHEMY CODE LAB

800+ hours of intensive remote Software **Engineering Training.** 

Multiple week-long remote project sprints focusing on group collaboration, TDD. planning, MVP deadlines, and app deployment [ 2020 - 2021

#### UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO

Software Design as an Element of the Software Development Lifecycle || 2019-2020

## CABRILLO COLLEGE

Computer Science and Art Theory || 2011-2012

## ABOUT

I'm a full stack software engineer based in Portland, OR specializing in building and designing exceptional websites, applications, and everything in between. My goal is to always build products that provide pixel-perfect performant experiences.

Currently, I am spending my free time working remotely on a variety of apps with a group of engineering friends.

## PROJECTS

#### FIIN || REPOLINK || LIVE SITE

React, CSS, Node.js, SQL, Express

FIIN is a React application for directors to submit a proposal to crowdfund a movie and then market and sell directly. Image hosting through Cloudinary.

My contribution with this app was creating general user flow and user experience, front-end design, and creating some other small functionality throughout the site.

#### CHERRY PLOTTER 2020 | REPO LINK

React, CSS, Node.js, SQL, Express

This project is a back end text based adventure game engine.

My contribution in this app was seeding the database, executing test driven development, and pair programming an example front-end for proof of concept using React and CSS. I love TDD so this was a really fun project for me.

#### GATHER APP | REPO LINK | LIVE SITE

React, Express, CSS, SQL, Node.js

Gather is a recipe application that allows users to browse, save recipes and contribute to food events with friends and family.

My contribution in this app was creating our pop up hamburger menu in React, creating the app logo, drawing out and executing general design outline, creating our scroll photo box, and pair programming the login/signup features using authorized routes in the back end and front end.

## TAROT APP || REPO LINK || LIVE SITE

JavaScript, HTML, CSS

This project was a tarot card reading application meant to engage users in an almost spiritual experience while getting their daily future or past and present read to them.

Major Arcana Divinator App is a user-friendly tarot reading app with aesthetically pleasing visuals and sounds, allowing the user to track past readings kept in local storage. With organization in mind and the ability to open our code to future expansion, we focused on clean code and structure in the backend. I loved this project and was involved in all aspects including front-end design, data-structure, and userflow.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PORTLAND, OR**

Freelance Full Stack Engineer and UX/UI Design (June 2019 - Current)

- Build and product manage accessible, beautiful, and functional products for multiple contract
- Worked independently and collaboratively on tech debt, API's, design, mobile apps, web apps, and debugged all while remote.

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER - PORTLAND, OR**

Alchemy Code Lab (Feb 2021 - July 2021)

- Assist senior dev staff with student instruction for full-stack Javascript curriculum.
- Debug code every day, explaining coding fundamentals, and code review.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER/OWNER - SANTA CRUZ, CA

Scorpio Moon(June 2018 - Aug 2020)

I decided to take my e-commerce site off of Etsy and built my own from scratch using vanilla JS, HTML, and CSS.